sportmonks.com 2019-09-28

# Privacy Policy - SportMonks

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. 

Also, as of May 25th 2018 the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is in place that modernizes and normalizes data privacy laws across Europe and applies to any organization collecting data on EU citizens. The GDPR gives EU citizens control of their digital data by empowering them with the right to know when personal data is being collected, what data is being collected, access to that data, and to purge it on request. 

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website. 

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, credit card information or other details to help you with your experience. 

We only collect information of you when you register on our site, subscribe to a plan, fill out a form or enter information on our site. 

We use the information we collect from you for a few reasons. 

  * Communication about the subscription and login process will be done via the email address you enter on the registration page.
  * Your email address will be used to send invoices related to your purchased products at SportMonks.
  * Credit card information will be used to bill you whenever you are subscribing to one of our plans.
  * Your email address is used for receiving our newsletter and or survey/marketing communication as well as customer related information emails via our Email Marketing tooling of MailChimp.

Furthermore, the information can be used for certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize user's experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To quickly process your transactions.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.
  * To follow up with them after correspondence (live chat, email or phone inquiries)

If a customer does not want to provide personal information like email address and credit card information he/she will not be able to use our services. For SportMonks this information is essential to serve our customers. 

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit card information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. 

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information. 

All payment transactions are processed through a payment gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our SportMonks servers. Our payment gateway provider is PCI Compliant and is certified as a  _PCI Level 1 Service Provider_. This is the most stringent level of certification available in the payments industry. 

We do not use Malware Scanning.

As long as you are a customer of us we will store and keep your personal information as this is essential to serve you as a customer. 

Whenever you want to cancel your registration as being a customer at SportMonks, we will remove all the personal information on our servers and payment gateway provider, we have of you within the legal time frame applicable. 

Note that unsubscribing from a paid plan still results in being a SportMonks customer with a Free Plan. Cancelling your registration as a Customer at SportMonks can be done be emailing to [registrations@sportmonks.com](mailto:registrations@sportmonks.com). Accordingly, we will remove your personal information as described above. 

GDPR compliance requires that you as a customer have certain rights that are relevant to the collection, processing, and storage of your personal data on SportMonks.com. 

Whenever you are logged in on SportMonks you will have the ability to change/rectify the Personal Information in your Settings. For example your email address, credit card information and address details. 

If you want to view all information we have of you, you can send us a mail to [registrations@sportmonks.com](mailto:registrations@sportmonks.com). We have a process in place to give you an overview of the personal information we have of you. It is also possible to make use of the right to be forgotten. This can also be requested by sending a mail to [registrations@sportmonks.com](mailto:registrations@sportmonks.com). 

If you have other questions related to these GDPR rights send us an email to [registrations@sportmonks.com](mailto:registrations@sportmonks.com) which is especially introduced for GDPR related questions and cancellations of registrations. 

Whenever you want to complaint about irregularities or your worries please contact us first via [registrations@sportmonks.com](mailto:registrations@sportmonks.com). Of course you also have the ability to log a complaint at a supervisory authority like the DPA. 

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. 

### We use cookies to:

  * Understand and save user's preferences for future visits.
  * ompile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. 

### If users disable cookies in their browser:

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It will turn off some of the features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. 

However, you can still place orders, Login and get API responses. 

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.

Third-party links 

We do not include or offer third-party products or services on our website.

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

  * We will notify the users via email Within 7 business days
  * We also agree to the Inpidual Redress Principle, which requires that inpiduals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that inpiduals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that inpiduals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations. 

If there are any questions regarding the GDPR or this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below. 

sportmonks.com 

SportMonks VOF
